Register to The Charles Ives Papers
Yale University Music Library
- Correspondence, Series III; 13 boxes
  - Correspondence - General, III.A
    - Slonimsky, Nicolas (Box 32B, Folder 1)
      - 1939 Apr 26, typed letter (copy) (Box 32A, Folder 5)
      - Harmony Twichell Ives, 1940 Sep 10; (copy) (Box 32A, Folder 5)
      - transcription of above by John Kirkpatrick (Box 32A, Folder 5)
      - Slonimsky, 1940 Oct 11; typed letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 5)
      - Charles Ives, 1940 Nov 24; (copy) (Box 32A, Folder 5)
      - Slonimsky, 1940 Nov 29; 2 typed letters signed (Box 32A, Folder 5)
      - Charles Ives for 1941 Aug 1, 2 drafts (Box 32A, Folder 5)
      - 1941 Aug 1, (copy) (Box 32A, Folder 5)
      - 1942? Jul 26, (copy) (Box 32A, Folder 5)
      - Slonimsky, 1945 Dec 28; typed letter (copy) (Box 32A, Folder 5)
      - 1946 Mar 16, typed letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 5)
      - Charles Ives, 1946 Mar 23; (copy) (Box 32A, Folder 5)
      - transcription of above by John Kirkpatrick (Box 32A, Folder 5)
      - Slonimsky (includes clipping), 1946 Mar 31; autograph letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 5)
      - 1946 Jul 15, typed letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 5)
      - Charles Ives for 1947 Jan 10 (verso draft to American Music Center), draft (Box 32A, Folder 5)
      - Charles Ives, 1947 Jan 10; (copy) (Box 32A, Folder 5)
      - transcription of above by John Kirkpatrick (Box 32A, Folder 5)
      - with photo of Adlow, 1948 Aug 8; clipping (Box 32A, Folder 5)
      - Charles Ives for 1948 Sep 15, draft (Box 32A, Folder 5)
      - transcription of above by John Kirkpatrick (Box 32A, Folder 5)
      - Charles Ives, 1948 Sep 15; (copy) (Box 32A, Folder 5)
      - Slonimsky, 1949 Oct 20; telegram (Box 32A, Folder 5)
      - Slonimsky and Adlow, 1951 Dec ?; postcard (Box 32A, Folder 5)
      - Slonimsky, 1952 Feb 28, Mar 21, 1952 Apr 3; 3 autograph letters signed (Box 32A, Folder 5)
      - re joke of Charles Ives, 1952 Mar; autograph memo (Box 32A, Folder 5)
      - Charles Ives, 1952 May 15, Oct 25; 2 (copy) (Box 32A, Folder 5)
      - transcription of above by John Kirkpatrick (Box 32A, Folder 5)
      - Adlow, 1953 Jan 8; autograph letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 5)
      - Slonimsky, 1953 Jul 13; typed letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 5)
      - for the above, 1953 Jul 14; envelope (Box 32A, Folder 5)
      - Charles Ives, 1953 Sep 2; (copy) (Box 32A, Folder 5)
      - transcription of above by John Kirkpatrick (Box 32A, Folder 5)
      - Slonimsky, 1954 May 20, Jul 16; 2 autograph letters signed (Box 32A, Folder 5)
      - Slonimsky, Electra, [1954? late]; autograph letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 5)
    - Smith, Carleton Sprague
    - Charles Ives to Smith, David Stanley, 1921 Nov 22; typed letter (copy) (Box 32A, Folder 6)
      - Smith, David Stanley, 1921 Nov 23; autograph letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 6)
    - Smith, Emma M., 1950 Apr 10; autograph letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 6)
    - Charles Ives to Smith, Max, 1922 Mar 12; autograph letter signed (copy) (Box 32A, Folder 6)
    - Soder-Hueck, Ada, 1922 Aug 19; autograph letter signed with enc (Box 32A, Folder 6)
    - Soifer, Joseph H, 1950 Jun 28; typed letter signed
      - Charles Ives to Soifer, no date; draft (Box 32A, Folder 6)
      - Soifer, 1950 Jul 11; typed letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 6)
    - Sonneck, Oscar G., 1923 Jul 5; typed letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 6)
    - Spaeth, Sigmund
      See also III.B/35/2/National Committee for American Music
      - Charles Ives to Spaeth?, no date; draft (Box 32A, Folder 6)
      - Harmony Twichell Ives to Spaeth, 1939 Feb 11; autograph letter (incomplete) (Box 32A, Folder 6)
      - Harmony Twichell Ives to Spaeth, 1939 March 17; autograph letter signed (copy) (Box 32A, Folder 6)
      - Charles and Harmony Ives, no date; draft for the above (Box 32A, Folder 6)
    - Spalding, Sara C., 1950 Jul 3; autograph letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 6)
    - Spencer, Enoch to Gordon, J.D., 1910 Oct 30; typed letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 6)
    - Spiers, F. Guthrie to Harmony Twichell Ives, 1937 Dec 2; autograph letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 6)
    - Spitzer, Jacqueline and Francis, 1947 May 2; 2 autograph letters signed (Box 32A, Folder 6)
    - Spivacke, Harold
      See III.B/34/14/Library of Congress
    - Spoel, Arnold, 1923 May 29; card (Box 32A, Folder 6)
    - Spry, Walton, 1922 Aug 30; autograph letter signed flyer (Box 32A, Folder 6)
    - Stanton, Mrs. Lawrence (Dorothy), no date [1950s]; autograph letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 6)
    - Stegmann with note Charles Ives, 1951 May 26, Jul 30; 2 autograph letters signed (Box 32A, Folder 6)
    - Stenderson, Lois, Nov 26; autograph letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 6)
      - Charles Ives to above, draft (Box 32A, Folder 6)
    - Stern, I.A., 1944 Dec 18; typed letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 6)
    - Stevens, Bruce, 1949 Dec 29; autograph letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 7)
    - Stietzel, Seth Mrs., 1947 May 8; autograph letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 7)
    - Stiles, Evelyn, [?] 1929; autograph letter signed
      - 1942 Jan 22, autograph postcard (Box 32A, Folder 7)
      - 1947 Aug 15, autograph letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 7)
    - Stokowski, Leopold (signed McGinty, M.A. for Stokowski), 1921 Jun 17; typed letter (Box 32A, Folder 7)
      - Stokowski with notes Charles Ives, 1932 May 12; typed letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 7)
    - Stone, Christopher
      See III.A/28/5/Cowell 1943 May 11
    - Charles Ives to Stone, Kurt, no date; draft (Box 32A, Folder 7)
      - 1949 Oct 26, typescript (copy) (Box 32A, Folder 7)
        See also III.B/34/4/Arrow
    - Strang, Gerald (Box 32A, Folder 7)
      See also III.B/35/6/New Music
    - Strang, 1934 Feb 12, Mar 31; 2 autograph postcards signed
      - 1934 Mar 12, typed postcard signed (Box 32A, Folder 7)
      - 1934 Apr 28, typed letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 7)
      - no date, autograph letter signed with lecture list (Box 32A, Folder 7)
      - Moe, Henry Allen (for Guggenheim) for Strang application, 1939 Nov 17; typed letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 7)
      - list of works, enc (Box 32A, Folder 7)
      - Strang, no date; 2 drafts (Box 32A, Folder 7)
      - Harmony Twichell Ives, 1939 Dec 20; autograph letter signed (copy) (Box 32A, Folder 7)
    - Charles Ives to Stransky, Josef, 1920 Apr 27; typed letter (copy)
      - Stransky, 1920 Apr 30; typed letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 7)
      - Charles Ives, 1921 Mar 9; typed letter signed (copy) (Box 32A, Folder 7)
      - Stransky's secretary (Henderson) 1921 Mar 13, typed letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 7)
    - Strasburger, Louis, 1935 Oct 24; autograph letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 7)
    - Stringham, Edwin, [?1921] Apr 2; typed letter signed
      - Charles Ives to above, [?1921] Jun 22; draft autograph letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 7)
      - Charles Ives, [?1921]; draft (Box 32A, Folder 7)
    - Swan, Verne S., 1938 May 12; 2 typed letters signed (Box 32A, Folder 7)
    - Charles Ives to Swanson, Allan, no date; draft
      - Swanson, 1951 Oct 18; typed letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 7)
      - Charles Ives, 1951 Oct 18; draft (Box 32A, Folder 7)
      - Swanson, 1952 Mar 13, Jun 17, 1952 Oct 19; 3 autograph letters signed (Box 32A, Folder 7)
    - Charles Ives to Sykes, James, 1939 [? ?]; draft (Box 32A, Folder 7)
      - Sykes, 1949 Oct 29; autograph letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 7)
    - Szigeti, Joseph
      See folder 32/8
    - Szyk, Arthur (American League for Free Palestine), no date; typed letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 7)
    - Szigeti, Joseph (Box 32A, Folder 8)
      - Charles Ives and verso draft Harmony Twichell Ives to Szigeti, no date; draft (Box 32A, Folder 8)
      - Szigeti, [?1942 Mar 1]; autograph letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 8)
      - Charles Ives to Szigeti with verso Newman, [?], no date; draft (Box 32A, Folder 8)
      - John Kirkpatrick to Szigeti, 1942? Feb 25; typed letter (copy) (Box 32A, Folder 8)
      - John Kirkpatrick, 1942 Mar 10; typed letter (copy) (Box 32A, Folder 8)
      - Charles Ives, no date; draft (Box 32A, Folder 8)
      - Szigeti secretary, Thomas, Mary, 1943 Feb 1; typed letter (Box 32A, Folder 8)
      - re Szigeti by Taubman, New York Times, article (Box 32A, Folder 8)
    - Charles Ives to Taft, William H., 1920 Jun 21; *typed (copy) (Box 32A, Folder 9)
      See also II.B/25/4/20th Amendment
    - Talmadge, David
      See III.C/37/1/Violin Sonata no. 4
    - Tapper, Thomas, 1921 Mar 19; typed letter signed and 2 envelopes (Box 32A, Folder 9)
      - Tapper, 1922 Aug 16; typed letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 9)
    - Taubman, Howard, 1949 Sep 15, Oct 11, 1949 Oct 25; 3 typed letters signed (Box 32A, Folder 9)
      See also III.A/32/8/Szigeti
    - Taylor, James, 1922 Aug 13; autograph letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 9)
    - Taylor, William, 1922 Sep 9; autograph letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 9)
      - Taylor, 1922 Oct 9; typed letter (Box 32A, Folder 9)
    - Teitz, Margot J.
      See III.B/34/15/Bomart
    - Tewksbury, 1943 Jun 22; autograph letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 9)
    - Charles Ives to Te[?]berry, no date; draft (Box 32A, Folder 9)
    - Charles Ives to Theremin, Leon, no date; draft (Box 32A, Folder 9)
    - Thomas, Paul, 1920 Jun 7; autograph letter (Box 32A, Folder 9)
    - Charles Ives to Thomson, Charles A., no date; draft (Box 32A, Folder 9)
    - Thompson, Douglas, 1934 Mar 16; autograph letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 9)
    - Tinker, Chauncey B.
      See III.B/35/3/National Institute of Arts and Letters
    - Tittle, Helen, 1951 Mar 16 or 6; autograph letter signed (enc clipping) (Box 32A, Folder 9)
    - Charles Ives to Todd, [?], no date; draft (Box 32A, Folder 9)
    - Tollersen, Carl, 1951 Jun 12, Nov 25; 2 typed letters signed (Box 32A, Folder 9)
    - Tompkins, Edward, 1935 Jan 10; autograph letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 9)
    - Travers, Patricia to American Music Center enc clipping, 1946 Dec 10; typed letter (copy)
      - Travers, 1947 Sep 17, Sep 22, 1947 Oct 8; 3 typed letters signed (Box 32A, Folder 9)
      - Travers, 1948 Apr 16, 1950 Jan 18, 1951 Apr 29, 1953 Feb 12; 4 autograph letters signed (Box 32A, Folder 9)
    - Trilling, L.R., 1936 Mar 12; typed letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 9)
    - Turitz, Esther, 1932 May 2; autograph letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 9)
      - Turitz, 1932 Jul 12; autograph letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 9)
    - Turley, Helen M., 1922 Oct 21; autograph letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 9)
    - Turner, Godfrey
    - Tweedy, Donald, 1921 Jan 3; autograph postcard
      - Tweedy, 1939 Dec 22; typed letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 9)
      - Charles Ives to Tweedy, no date; 2 drafts (Box 32A, Folder 9)
      - Tweedy, 1939 Dec 29; autograph letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 9)
      - Tweedy, no date; printed card (Box 32A, Folder 9)
    - Twichell Family
      See III.A/33/3 & 4
    - Twichell, Burton (Box 32A, Folder 10)
      See also 30/9/Ives, Moss
      - Twichell to "Meg" [Harmony Twichell Ives], [?] Apr 17; autograph letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 10)
      - Twichell, 1918 Jan [?]; autograph letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 10)
      - Twichell, 1918 Jan 23; telegram (Box 32A, Folder 10)
      - Twichell to Meg, 1923 Jun 19; typed letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 10)
      - Twichell to Meg, 1942 Jan 18, Feb 26; 2 autograph letters signed (Box 32A, Folder 10)
      - Meg (enc printed poem), 1942 Mar 23; typed letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 10)
      - Twichell to Meg, 1942 Mar 31; autograph letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 10)
      - Twichell to Meg, 1942 May 22; autograph postcard signed (Box 32A, Folder 10)
      - Twichell, Mrs. Burton (Katherine) to Harmony Twichell Ives, 1951 Oct 8; autograph letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 10)
    - Twichell, Charles, no date, [?] Jan 1, [?] Dec 26; 3 autograph letters signed
      - Twichell, with envelope, 1941 Jan 1, 1941 Dec 30; 2 autograph letters signed (Box 32A, Folder 10)
      - Twichell, 1943 Jan 5; autograph letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 10)
    - Charles Ives to Twichell, Dave, [1903 Sep or Oct]; autograph letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 10)
    - for Twichell, Joseph H., 1939 Apr 9; sermon (copy)
      - Twichell, Joseph H., 1940 Jan 26; typed letter (copy) (Box 32A, Folder 10)
      - Twichell, 1947 May 8, 1949 Oct 24; 2 typed letters signed (Box 32A, Folder 10)
    - Twichell, Mrs. Joseph (Esther), 1943 Dec; card signed (Box 32A, Folder 10)
    - Twichell, Sarah D., 1950 Apr 12; program with note (Box 32A, Folder 10)
      - Twichell, Harmony to Charles Ives, [1906] Dec 12; autograph letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 10)
    - Twichell, "Sally", no date; 6 autograph letters signed (incomplete) (Box 32A, Folder 10)
    - Tyler, [Edie] for "Kitty", no date; Birthday card
      - Tyler, Edie and George, no date; Birthday card (Box 32A, Folder 10)
      - Tyler, no date; Christmas card (Box 32A, Folder 10)
      - Tyler, [Edie and George] to Charles Ives, 194; 2 Birthday cards (Box 32A, Folder 10)
      - Tyler, George to Harmony Twichell Ives, 1962 May 23; autograph letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 10)
        III.A/28/8/Cowell 1955 May 20
    - Underwood, Sophie K., 1948 Feb 27; typed letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 11)
    - Upton, William Treat, 1931 Dec 5; typed letter signed
      - Upton, 1931 Dec 6; autograph letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 11)
      - Charles Ives, no date; 2 drafts (Box 32A, Folder 11)
    - VanDyck, Ernest, 1922 Aug 18; postcard (Box 32A, Folder 11)
    - VanHorne, with note Charles Ives, no date; clipping (Box 32A, Folder 11)
    - Van Noorden, 1923 May 25; autograph postcard signed (Box 32A, Folder 11)
    - Van Patteu, Nathan
      See III.A/28/8/Cowell 1951 Aug
    - Van Winckle, May, no date, 1933 Jun 17, 1943 Mar 24 or 25; 3 autograph letters signed (Box 32A, Folder 11)
    - Charles Ives to Van Wyck, Mrs. Harmony Twichell Ives hand, [1920s]; Christmas card (Box 32A, Folder 11)
      - Charles Ives to Van Wyck, Amelia, 1928 Oct 15; typed letter (Box 32A, Folder 11)
        John Kirkpatrick Papers
        Perlis private collection
    - Verplanck, William
      - Verplanck, 1908 Feb 8; typed letter signed with envelope and card (Box 32A, Folder 11)
      - 1931 [? ?], typed letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 11)
      - 1937 Sep 23, typed letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 11)
      - 1934 Jul 5, 2 autograph letters signed (Box 32A, Folder 11)
      - 1935 Jul 2, enc clipping (Box 32A, Folder 11)
      - 1937 Sep 30, 1939 Aug 1, 1939 Dec 29, 3 typed letters signed (Box 32A, Folder 11)
      - 1940 Jan 21, autograph letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 11)
      - 1941 May 27, Jun 11, 1941 Nov 14, 24, 27, 1941 Dec 10, 1942 Jan 12, 7 typed letters signed (Box 32A, Folder 11)
      - 1942 May 27, autograph letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 11)
      - Verplancks, no date; telegram (Box 32A, Folder 11)
      - no date, Easter card (Box 32A, Folder 11)
      - no date, New Year's card (Box 32A, Folder 11)
    - Vogt, Mrs. Leroy, 1953 Oct 26; autograph letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 11)
    - Charles Ives to Von Sternberg, Constantin, no date; draft (Box 32A, Folder 11)
    - Wagenknecht
      See III.A/31/6/Phelps
    - Wagenknecht, Edward, 1938 Apr, 2; article (Box 32A, Folder 12)
      - Harmony Twichell Ives, 1937 Jan 1; typed letter (copy) (Box 32A, Folder 12)
      - Wagenknecht, 1937 Jan 18; typed letter (copy) (Box 32A, Folder 12)
    - Walker, Joan, 1953 Mar 10; autograph letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 12)
    - Wallenstein, Alfred
      See III.B/34/16/Musical Congress Committee 1944 Jan 7
    - Waller, Mrs. L., 1922 Sep 7; autograph ltyped letter signeder signed (Box 32A, Folder 12)
      - Charles Ives to Waller, 1922 Sep 13; (copy) (Box 32A, Folder 12)
    - Walsh, James E., Mrs., 1939 Jan 27; autograph letter signed and copy (Box 32A, Folder 12)
      - Harmony Twichell Ives to above, no date; draft (Box 32A, Folder 12)
    - Walton, Blanche, no date; autograph letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 12)
    - Wardle, Constance, 1952 Feb 29; typed letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 12)
    - Ware, Edward, 1920 May 28; autograph letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 12)
    - Ware, Edward Mrs. (Alice H.), 1921 Mar 7; autograph letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 12)
    - Warsham, Edwin, 1923 Jun 28; autograph letter signed (enc brochure) (Box 32A, Folder 12)
    - Washburn, Watson, 1939 Mar 7, 1947 May 6; 2 typed letters signed (Box 32A, Folder 12)
    - Waters, Edward
      See III.B/36/8/Yale Music Library
    - Charles Ives to Weber, May [?], no date; draft (Box 32A, Folder 12)
    - Weiner, Leo, 1922 Sep 1; autograph letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 12)
    - Weisbord, Ray, 1953 Mar 18; typed letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 12)
      - no date, brochure with note (Box 32A, Folder 12)
    - Charles Ives to Weishaus, [1929]; draft (Box 32A, Folder 12)
    - Weiss, Adolph
      See also III.B/35/5/Native American Composers
      - Weiss, Adolph, 1934 Jul 15; typed postcard signed (Box 32A, Folder 12)
      - Weiss, Adolph and Mary, 1935 Nov 4; autograph postcard signed (Box 32A, Folder 12)
      - 1936 Mar 26, card/note signed (Box 32A, Folder 12)
      - Weiss to Tyler, Edith, 1942 Jul 14; typed letter signed with envelope (Box 32A, Folder 12)
    - Weiss, Mr. and Mrs. Adolph, 1945 Dec 12; Christmas card (Box 32A, Folder 12)
      - with Charles Ives marginalia, no date; typed letter signed (fragment) (Box 32A, Folder 12)
    - Welles, Sumner
      See III.B/36/3/United Nations
    - Wells, Thomas
      See 27/8/Bellamann 1922 Aug 11
    - Wenzel, Fred P., 1949 Nov 4; *typed (copy) (Box 32A, Folder 12)
    - Wertheim, Alma, 1932 [Aug 20 or May 2?]; autograph letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 12)
      - Charles Ives to above, no date; 2 drafts (Box 32A, Folder 12)
    - White, James T.
      See III.B/35/2/National Cyclopedia
    - White, Camilla
    - White, Laura T., 1921 Mar 7, [1923] Apr 22; 2 autograph letters signed (Box 32A, Folder 12)
    - Whitmer, Carl (Box 32A, Folder 13)
      - John Kirkpatrick, listing (Box 32A, Folder 13)
      - Whitmer, Carl, program (copy) (Box 32A, Folder 13)
      - Charles Ives, 1921 Jun 26; autograph letter signed (copy) (Box 32A, Folder 13)
      - Whitmer, 1921 Mar 15; typed letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 13)
      - Whitmer, Carl, program (Box 32A, Folder 13)
      - Whitmer, Carl, programs (copy) (Box 32A, Folder 13)
      - Whitmer, 1922 Sep 10; autograph card signed (Box 32A, Folder 13)
      - 1922 Sep 16, typed letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 13)
      - 1922, Christmas cards (Box 32A, Folder 13)
      - 1923 Sep 8, typed letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 13)
      - Charles Ives, [1923 ?]; draft (Box 32A, Folder 13)
      - transcription by John Kirkpatrick (Box 32A, Folder 13)
      - Whitmer, 1924 Jan ?; autograph letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 13)
      - Charles Ives, 1924 Jan 11; typed letter (copy) (Box 32A, Folder 13)
      - Whitmer, 1924 Jan 23; typed letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 13)
      - Whitmer, 1924 Jan 29; typed letter (copy) (Box 32A, Folder 13)
      - 1924 Feb [3], typed letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 13)
      - Whitmer, Carl, enc program (Box 32A, Folder 13)
      - Charles Ives, 1924 Feb 8; typed letter (copy) (Box 32A, Folder 13)
      - 1924 May 6, Jun 10, programs (copy) (Box 32A, Folder 13)
      - Whitmer, 1924 Nov 25, 1925 Jan 17, with envelope 1925 Feb 8, 1924 May 21, 1925 [? ?], 1925 [? ?]; 6 typed letters signed (Box 32A, Folder 13)
      - Whitmer, Carl, brochure from scrapbook #4, p. 81 (Box 32A, Folder 13)
      - Whitmer, 1927 Jan 26, Feb 18; 2 typed letters signed (Box 32A, Folder 13)
      - Charles Ives, 1927 Feb 21; typed letter (copy) (Box 32A, Folder 13)
      - 1927 May 17, autograph letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 13)
      - Charles Ives, 1927 Jun 8; typed letter (copy) "not sent" (Box 32A, Folder 13)
      - 1927 Sep 11, Nov 10, 2 autograph letters signed (Box 32A, Folder 13)
      - Whitmer, Carl, program from scrapbook #4, p. 80 (Box 32A, Folder 13)
      - Nov 27, autograph letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 13)
      - Whitmer, Carl, verso Charles Ives note (Box 32A, Folder 13)
      - Whitmer, [?] Dec 27, 1928 Jan 12, Jan 25, [1928?] May 22; 4 autograph letters signed (Box 32A, Folder 14)
      - 1928 Jul 3, autograph card signed (Box 32A, Folder 14)
      - 1928 Dec 27, typed letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 14)
      - Charles Ives, 1929 Jan 13; autograph letter signed (copy) (Box 32A, Folder 14)
      - 1929 Jan 18, Feb 6, 2 typed letters signed (Box 32A, Folder 14)
      - [?] Mar 29, autograph letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 14)
      - 1929 Mar 13, typed letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 14)
      - Charles Ives, 1929 Mar 24, Jun 18; 2 autograph letters signed (copy) (Box 32A, Folder 14)
      - 1939 Jun 18, typed letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 14)
      - Charles Ives, 1929 Jun 25; autograph letter signed (copy) (Box 32A, Folder 14)
      - [?]1929 Oct 10, program with note from Whitmer (Box 32A, Folder 14)
      - 1929 Nov mid, typed letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 14)
      - Charles Ives, 1929 Dec 30; autograph letter signed (copy) (Box 32A, Folder 14)
      - Whitmer, [Helen?], no date; announcement exhibit (Box 32A, Folder 14)
      - 1930 Jan 1, autograph letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 14)
      - ?1930 Feb ?, typed letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 14)
      - 1930 Mar 18, program (copy) (Box 32A, Folder 14)
      - "Dramamount", 1930 Mar 18; program (Box 32A, Folder 14)
      - [? Mar ?], autograph letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 14)
      - 1930, announcement (Box 32A, Folder 14)
      - Whitmer, Carl, card (Box 32A, Folder 14)
      - [? 1930], typed letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 14)
      - talk by Whitmer, no date; brochure (Box 32A, Folder 14)
      - Whitmer, (Helen?] to Harmony Twichell Ives, 1930 Christmas; autograph letter (Box 32A, Folder 14)
      - [? 1931], autograph letter signed (copy) (Box 32A, Folder 14)
      - transcription by John Kirkpatrick (Box 32A, Folder 14)
      - 1931 Apr 29, program (Box 32A, Folder 14)
      - 1931 Apr 3, review (Box 32A, Folder 14)
      - [?1931], autograph letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 14)
      - 1931 [May 24?], manuscript page (copy)? (Box 32A, Folder 14)
      - Charles Ives see program file, program (copy) (Box 32A, Folder 14)
      - Whitmer, 1931 May 25; autograph letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 14)
      - Whitmer, Helen, [?1931 Oct ?]; autograph letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 14)
      - 1931 Nov ?, typed letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 14)
      - 1931 Dec 23, autograph letter signed (Box 32A, Folder 14)
      - from scrapbook #4, p. 82, 2 programs (Box 32B, Folder 15)
      - Charles Ives, 1932 Dec [?]; autograph letter signed (copy) (Box 32B, Folder 15)
      - no date, autograph postcard signed and transcription by John Kirkpatrick (Box 32B, Folder 15)
      - 1933 Jan 9, autograph letter signed (Box 32B, Folder 15)
      - 1932 or 1933, program (Box 32B, Folder 15)
      - 1933 Jul 14, autograph postcard signed (Box 32B, Folder 15)
      - Charles Ives, 1933? Jul [?]; autograph letter signed (copy) (Box 32B, Folder 15)
      - 1935 Mar 24, autograph letter signed (Box 32B, Folder 15)
      - from scrapbook #4, p. 174, 1935 Mar 20; program (Box 32B, Folder 15)
      - 1938 Sep 25 [?], autograph letter signed (Box 32B, Folder 15)
      - Charles Ives for, 1938 Sep 27; draft (Box 32B, Folder 15)
      - Advertiser Recording Service, Inc., 1938 Sep 28; typed letter signed (Box 32B, Folder 15)
      - for Whitmer, order (Box 32B, Folder 15)
      - Harmony Twichell Ives draft for 1938 [Sep 30?], verso (Box 32B, Folder 15)
      - 1938 Oct 6, autograph letter signed (Box 32B, Folder 15)
      - 1939 Aug 20, new article (Box 32B, Folder 15)
      - 1939 Sep 10, autograph letter signed (Box 32B, Folder 15)
      - Charles Ives for 1939 Nov 3, no date; draft (Box 32B, Folder 15)
      - Charles Ives, 1939 Nov 3; autograph letter signed (copy) (Box 32B, Folder 15)
      - 1940 Oct 29, autograph letter signed (Box 32B, Folder 15)